<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
GentiumPlus-webfont-example.html
Gentium Plus v1.501-test
6 Oct 2010
This file is part of Gentium Plus font family (http://scripts.sil.org/Gentium)
and is Copyright (c) 2003-2010 SIL International (http://www.sil.org/),
with Reserved Font Names "Gentium" and "SIL". This Font Software is licensed
under the SIL Open Font License, Version 1.1. You should have received a copy
of the license along with this Font Software. If this is not the case, go to
(http://scripts.sil.org/OFL) for all the details including a FAQ.
-->
<?oxygen RNGSchema="woffmeta.rng" type="xml"?>
<metadata version="1.0">
    <uniqueid id="org.sil.fonts.gentiumplus.1501" />
    <vendor name="SIL International" url="http://scripts.sil.org" />
    <credits>
        <credit
            name="Victor Gaultney"
            url="http://www.sil.org/~gaultney/"
            role="Original Designer" />
        <credit
            name="Annie Olsen"
            url="http://scripts.sil.org/"
            role="Contributed some extended Latin glyphs" />
        <credit
            name="Iska Routamaa"
            url="http://scripts.sil.org/"
            role="Contributed some extended Latin glyphs and extensive work on the italic" />
        <credit
        	name="SIL font engineers"
        	url="http://scripts.sil.org/"
        	role="OpenType code and build support" />
    </credits>
    <description>
        <text lang="en">
			Gentium ("belonging to the nations" in Latin) is a Unicode typeface family 
			designed to enable the many diverse ethnic groups around the world who use 
			the Latin, Cyrillic and Greek scripts to produce readable, high-quality
			publications. The design is intended to be highly readable, reasonably
			compact, and visually attractive. Gentium has won a "Certificate of Excellence
			in Typeface Design" in two major international typeface design competitions: 
			bukva:raz! (2001), TDC2003 (2003).

			The Gentium Plus font family is based on the original design. It currently 
			comes with regular and italic face only, although additional weights are in
			develoment.

			The goal for this product is to provide a single Unicode-based font family
			that contains a comprehensive inventory of glyphs needed for almost any
			Roman- or Cyrillic-based writing system, whether used for phonetic or
			orthographic needs, and provide a matching Greek face. In addition, there
			is provision for other characters and symbols useful to linguists. This
			font makes use of state-of-the-art font technologies to support complex
			typographic issues, such as the need to position arbitrary combinations
			of base glyphs and diacritics optimally.

			Two fonts from this typeface family are included in this release:

			     * Gentium Plus Regular
			     * Gentium Plus Italic

			Work is ongoing to provide bold and bold-italic weights, as well as a
			complete book-weight family.

			For detailed documentation see the contents of the 'documentation' folder.


			ChangeLog
			---------
			(This should list both major and minor changes, most recent first.)

			1 Sep 2010 (SIL NRSI team) Gentium Plus version 1.501-test beta release
			- FOR TESTING ONLY
			- Regular and Italic weights only
			- New OpenType and Graphite support
			- New extended Cyrillic script support, inc. Serbian alternates
			- Character set and features up to same level as Charis SIL 4.106
			- Support for more historic Greek characters and alternate seriffed beta
			- No separate GentiumAlt fonts (replaced by font features)

			28 Nov 2005 (Victor Gaultney)  Gentium version 1.02
			- Changed licensing to the SIL Open Font License
			- Included FontLab source files
			- Fixed some duplicate PostScript glyph names
			- Fixed italic angle

			19 Sep 2003 (Victor Gaultney)  Gentium version 1.01 
			- Maintenance release focused on changing internal font
			- Information to reflect the changeover to an SIL project
			- There is only one bug fix - the Greek mu PS name was changed to try and fix 
			a display/printing problem. There is still no manual hinting.

			16 Sep 2002 (Victor Gaultney)  Gentium version 1.00
			- First public release
			- No manual hinting is included in this version. Some has been done - with 
			good results - but is not yet complete enough.
		</text>
    </description>
    <license url="http://scripts.sil.org/ofl"
             id="org.sil.ofl.11">
        <text lang="en">
			Copyright (c) 2003-2010 SIL International (http://www.sil.org/),
			with Reserved Font Names "Gentium" and "SIL".

			This Font Software is licensed under the SIL Open Font License, Version 1.1.
			This license is copied below, and is also available with a FAQ at:
			http://scripts.sil.org/OFL


			-----------------------------------------------------------
			SIL OPEN FONT LICENSE Version 1.1 - 26 February 2007
			-----------------------------------------------------------

			PREAMBLE
			The goals of the Open Font License (OFL) are to stimulate worldwide
			development of collaborative font projects, to support the font creation
			efforts of academic and linguistic communities, and to provide a free and
			open framework in which fonts may be shared and improved in partnership
			with others.

			The OFL allows the licensed fonts to be used, studied, modified and
			redistributed freely as long as they are not sold by themselves. The
			fonts, including any derivative works, can be bundled, embedded, 
			redistributed and/or sold with any software provided that any reserved
			names are not used by derivative works. The fonts and derivatives,
			however, cannot be released under any other type of license. The
			requirement for fonts to remain under this license does not apply
			to any document created using the fonts or their derivatives.

			DEFINITIONS
			"Font Software" refers to the set of files released by the Copyright
			Holder(s) under this license and clearly marked as such. This may
			include source files, build scripts and documentation.

			"Reserved Font Name" refers to any names specified as such after the
			copyright statement(s).

			"Original Version" refers to the collection of Font Software components as
			distributed by the Copyright Holder(s).

			"Modified Version" refers to any derivative made by adding to, deleting,
			or substituting -- in part or in whole -- any of the components of the
			Original Version, by changing formats or by porting the Font Software to a
			new environment.

			"Author" refers to any designer, engineer, programmer, technical
			writer or other person who contributed to the Font Software.

			PERMISSION &amp; CONDITIONS
			Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining
			a copy of the Font Software, to use, study, copy, merge, embed, modify,
			redistribute, and sell modified and unmodified copies of the Font
			Software, subject to the following conditions:

			1) Neither the Font Software nor any of its individual components,
			in Original or Modified Versions, may be sold by itself.

			2) Original or Modified Versions of the Font Software may be bundled,
			redistributed and/or sold with any software, provided that each copy
			contains the above copyright notice and this license. These can be
			included either as stand-alone text files, human-readable headers or
			in the appropriate machine-readable metadata fields within text or
			binary files as long as those fields can be easily viewed by the user.

			3) No Modified Version of the Font Software may use the Reserved Font
			Name(s) unless explicit written permission is granted by the corresponding
			Copyright Holder. This restriction only applies to the primary font name as
			presented to the users.

			4) The name(s) of the Copyright Holder(s) or the Author(s) of the Font
			Software shall not be used to promote, endorse or advertise any
			Modified Version, except to acknowledge the contribution(s) of the
			Copyright Holder(s) and the Author(s) or with their explicit written
			permission.

			5) The Font Software, modified or unmodified, in part or in whole,
			must be distributed entirely under this license, and must not be
			distributed under any other license. The requirement for fonts to
			remain under this license does not apply to any document created
			using the Font Software.

			TERMINATION
			This license becomes null and void if any of the above conditions are
			not met.

			DISCLAIMER
			THE FONT SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
			EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO ANY WARRANTIES OF
			MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT
			OF COPYRIGHT, PATENT, TRADEMARK, OR OTHER RIGHT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
			COPYRIGHT HOLDER BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY,
			INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
			DAMAGES, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
			FROM, OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE FONT SOFTWARE OR FROM
			OTHER DEALINGS IN THE FONT SOFTWARE.
		</text>
    </license>
    <copyright>
        <text lang="en">Copyright (c) 2003-2010 SIL International (http://www.sil.org/)</text>
    </copyright>
    <trademark>
        <text lang="en">Gentium is a trademark of SIL International</text>
    </trademark>
</metadata>
